{
    "id": "1f294aca056e4c49aa28deded92f3cf4",
    "title": "Phrasal Verbs With Do And Make",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "95e46be0c82b45a1854010617e9e9770",
            "title": "Phrasal Verbs With Do and Make",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "We cannot ..................... without food or water.",
                    "description": "To do without something is to manage without that.",
                    "answers": [
                        "do",
                        "with",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Child marriage is a bad custom and should be ………………. with.",
                    "description": "To do away with a custom is to abolish it.",
                    "answers": [
                        "done off",
                        "done away",
                        "done up"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "His elder brother did him ………………… his rightful inheritance.",
                    "description": "To do someone out of something is to prevent them from having it.",
                    "answers": [
                        "out",
                        "of",
                        "out of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We are ……………….. the kitchen on the weekend.",
                    "description": "To do up the kitchen is to renovate it.",
                    "answers": [
                        "making up",
                        "doing up",
                        "doing out"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "As soon as the thief saw the dog rushing towards him, he ……………… the gate.",
                    "description": "To make for the door is to move in the direction of the door.",
                    "answers": [
                        "made out",
                        "made for",
                        "made off"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "What do you make ……………….. her new boyfriend?",
                    "description": "Make of means think of.",
                    "answers": [
                        "out",
                        "of",
                        "off",
                        "up"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He made ……………….. as soon as he heard that his mother had fallen ill.",
                    "description": "To make off is to leave hurriedly.",
                    "answers": [
                        "up",
                        "off",
                        "out"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The superb food at the restaurant made ………………… the bad service.",
                    "description": "To make up for something is to compensate for it. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "out for",
                        "for",
                        "up for"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The boy made ……………….. to his mother until she allowed him to go to the movies.",
                    "description": "To make up to somebody is to be nice to them with objective of getting something.",
                    "answers": [
                        "up",
                        "out",
                        "off"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The human body is ………………… of the five elements.",
                    "description": "Make up means compose or constitute.",
                    "answers": [
                        "made out",
                        "made up",
                        "made off"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I find it rather difficult to make him ……………..",
                    "description": "To make somebody out is to understand them.",
                    "answers": [
                        "up",
                        "out",
                        "off"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I always fight with my husband but we …………………. soon after.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "do up",
                        "make off",
                        "make up"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}